Desmond O'Grady papers, 1953-2001
Emory University
- Printed material, 1953-2001, Series 5; Boxes 64 - 77, OP 2-12
  - Other printed material, 1953-2000, Subseries 5.3; Boxes 69 - 77
    - Annals of the Kingdom of Ireland (Box 69, Folder 34)
    - The Fourth Year (Box 69, Folder 35)
    - Magazines and pamphlets
    - Akzente, February 1997 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - American University in Cairo Telephone Directory, 1988/89 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Anvil Press Poetry Catalog, 1987/8, Winter 1984-Spring 1985, Autumn 1992, and March 1997 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Art Matters, October 2001 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - The Arts Plan 1999-2001 Pamphlets (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Athens Centre for the Creative Arts Pamphlet (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - The Ballybeg Backlist 1998 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Blackstaff Press Catalogs, 1996-1999 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Bloodaxe Books Catalog (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - The Bottom Dog, 9 June 1978 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Bulletin of the Department of Foreign Affairs, July/August 1984 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Cara, November/December 1986 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Cavan Arts Newsletter, October-December 1991 and May-July 1992 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Chicago Review, Summer 1997 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Collector's Mart Magazine, September-October, 1995 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Columbia Writers, September 1974 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - The Cork Review, March/April, 1980 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Corristoona Ledger, December 1994 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Courvoiser's Book of the Best (Box 70, Folder 19)
    - Dedalus Catalog (Box 70, Folder 20)
    - Department of Labour Work Plan (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - Dingle: A Guide Book (Box 70, Folder 22)
    - Dover Book Catalog, Fall 1995 (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - Dublin Evening Post, 12 September, 1807 (Box OP5)
    - Dublin Opinion, March 1953 (Box 70, Folder 24)
    - Duckworth Catalog, Autumn 1996 (Box 70, Folder 25)
    - Eigse: A Journal of Irish Studies (Box 70, Folder 26)
    - From the C entre, November/December 1997 and April/May 1999 (Box 70, Folder 27)
    - For Socrates: The Centres of Light and Learning (Box 70, Folder 28)
    - The Gallery Press Stocklist, Summer/Autumn 1999 (Box 70, Folder 29)
    - Grants and Awards Available to Foreign Writers Pamphlet (Box 70, Folder 30)
    - Guide of Pescia (Box 70, Folder 31)
    - Harvill News, Spring 1993 (Box 70, Folder 32)
    - Head-of-the-Charles Regatta Program (Box 70, Folder 33)
    - The Houghton Library Pamphlet (Box 70, Folder 34)
    - Il Caffe del Teatro (Box 70, Folder 35)
    - Il Castello e la Badia di Torrechiara (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - ILE Newsletter, No. 3, 1997 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - The International IMPAC Dublin Literary Award Pamphlet (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - International Writers' Conference Programme (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - The Ireland Funds Pamphlet (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Ireland Today, 1979-1985 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - The Irish Herald, May 2000 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - The Irish Literary Supplement, Spring 1985 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Irish Translators' Association Newsletter, March 1990-March 1992 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - The Jerusalem Post, 15-21 April, 1979 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Jubilaeum: La Via Francigena Pamphlet (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Kavafis Museum in Alexandria Pamphlet (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Kinsale Newsletter, February 1995 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Library Newsletter, May 1999 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Limerick Socialist, February 1973-December 1975 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Limerick Socialist, January 1976-November 1978 (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Limerick Socialist, January-June 1979 and miscellaneous pages (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Literary Review, August 1989 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - London Review of Books, 18 July, 1985 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Magill, August 1988 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Marginalia, Numbers 2, 4, 6, 10, 11, 17, and 19 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Modern Hebrew Literature, Autumn 1977 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Munster Literature Centre Newsletter Plus, 1997-1998 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - The New York Review of Books, 16 June, 1983 (Box OP6)
    - The New Yorker, August 23 and 30, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Newsweek, 1 January, 1979 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - North Dakota Quarterly, Winter 1989 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Nuacht, Winter 1982-83, Spring 1983 and April-May 1991 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - The Old Limerick Journal, 1980-1986 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Owl, November 1989 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Pamphlet outlining the recommended merger of Norwich Union and CGU (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Pearl, Fall-Winter 1978 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Pilgrim Book Catalog (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - P.N. Review, September/October 1991 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Poetry Ireland, Spring 1968 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Poetry Ireland News, February-December 1997 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Poets in Cahoots, No. 1 and 2 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Revolutionary Calender 1982 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Rivista Di Studi Anglo-Americani, 28-30 October 1993 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Roscrea Review, Spring 1999 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - The Roxbury Latin School Newsletter, October 1981, April 1982, and October 1982 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Sbandieratori dei Terzieri Massetani (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Seventh International Congress of Celtic Studies Pamphlet (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - S.H.Y., Midsummer 1977 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - The Spectator (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - St. Anthony's College of the Irish Fanciscans Louvain Pamphlet (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - The Stanford Humanities Center Pamphlet (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Starlight (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Summary of Health Services Pamphlet (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - 10th Muse 9, 1999 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - Thessaloniki '97 Brochure (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - The Third Kavafis International Symposium Cairo and Alexandria Program (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - Time, 8 September, 1986 (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Towards a New Framework for the Arts: A Review of Arts Legislation (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - The Tyrone Guthrie Centre in the 1990's (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - The Tyrone Guthrie Centre Pamphlet (Box 73, Folder 23)
    - Ubu 4 (Box 73, Folder 24)
    - Wanted in Rome, 19 February, 1997 (Box 73, Folder 25)
    - Writ, May-June 1982 (Box 73, Folder 26)
    - Art exhibit pamphlets
    - Beermann, Trautl (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Brady, Michael (Box OP7)
    - Brockstedt, Conrad (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Burke, John (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Caro, Anthony, Trajan Markets Rome (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Davey, Rosaleen (Box OP8)
    - Farr, Patsy (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Fitzgerald (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Fitzgerald, Joan, Dieci Bronzetti 1984 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Gay, Madame Myriam, Bricka (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Gillespie, Rowan (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Hadzi, Dimitri (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Holzapfel, Michelle (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Holzapfel, David and Michelle, Applewoods (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Holzapgel, David and Michelle (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Jackson, Raoul Peter (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Klee, Paul (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Kontrec, Anita (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - le Brocquy, Louis, Studies Towards an Image of William Shakespeare (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - le Brocquy, Louis, The Tain (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - MacNeice, Corinna, Weighting Measures (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - McSweeney, Sean (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - Murray, John Philip, Demiurge-Drawing Words (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - Murray, John Philip (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Piroska, Szanto (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - Robinson, Carol, Moment of Light (Box 74, Folder 24)
    - Salamanca, Manuel (Box 74, Folder 25)
    - Shinnors, John (Box 74, Folder 26)
    - Multiple or unidentified artists
    - Moto Perpetuo (Box 74, Folder 27)
    - The 77 Exhibition (Box 74, Folder 28)
    - Stone Sculpture: A Contemporary Art Form from Zimbabwe (Box 74, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous/Newspaper clippings
    - Business cards (Box 74, Folder 30)
    - Maps (Box 74, Folder 31)
    - Menus (Box 74, Folder 32)
    - Tickets (Box 74, Folder 33)
    - Newspaper clippings--Art (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings--Literature (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings--Literature (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings--Politics (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings--Religion (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings--Reviews (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings--Reviews (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings--Theatre (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings--Miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings--Miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Promotional items
    - Promotional items (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Promotional items (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Promotional items (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Promotional items (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Promotional items (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Poster for Vincenzo Cardarelli (Box OP9)
    - Posters for Kavanagh's Yearly, 1991 (Box OP10)
    - Posters for Kinsale Arts Week, 1988 (Box OP11)
    - Poster for The Theory and Practice of Literary Translation, Spring 1998 (Box OP12)
- Photographs, Series 6; Box 78
  The series contains photographs of O'Grady, his family, and others.
  - Desmond O'Grady (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Family (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Artistic photographs (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Others (Box 78, Folder 4)
Index to Selected Correspondence
Astley, Neil 1990 September 14, ALS, 1p [DO to NA] 1990 December 29, ALS, 1p [DO to NA] 1991 June 26, TLS, 1p 1997 ca April 3, ALS, 1p 1998 November 6, ALS, 2p [DO to NA] undated, TLS, 1p undated, ALS,1p [DO to NA]
Banville, John 1988, October 20, TLS, 1p 1991, July 29, TLS, 1p
Beckett, Samuel 1980 August 1, TLS, 1p [DO to SB] 1983 February 9, ALS, 1p 1985, December 8, ALS, 1p [photocopy] 1986, April 24, ALS, 1p [photocopy] undated, ALS, 1p
Bolger, Dermot 1989, April 3, TLS, 2p 1989, April 17, TLS, 1p 1989, June 15, TLS, 2p 1989, July 3, ALS, 1p [DO to DB] 1989, August 21, ALS, 1p [DO to DB] 1989, September 5, ALS, 1p [DO to DB] 1989, October 3, TLS, 3p 1989, November 6, TLS, 1p 1992, June 25, TLS, 2p 1992, July 13, post card [DO to DB] 1992, September 18, TLS, 1p undated, TLS, 1p undated, TLS, 1p
Brodsky, Joseph 1987, November 25, ALS, 1p [DO to JB] 1988, May 31, post card [DO to JB]
Dorgan, Theo 1990 February 13, ALS, 1p 1992 June 24, TLS, 1p 1997 August 11, ALS, 1p[DO to TD] 1997 October 6, ALS, 1p 2000 April 3, ALS, 1p [DO to TD] 2000 April 7, ALS, 1p [DO to TD] 2000 April 25, ALS, 1p [DO to TD] 2000 August 16, post card undated, ALS, 1p
Egan, Desmond 1974 November 5, ALS, 1p [DO to DE] 1974 November 20, post card 1978 March 25, ALS, 1p 1985 October 10, TLS, 1p 1988 May 21, ALS, 1p 1993 May 28, ALS, 1p
Ellmann, Richard 1977 May 9, TLS, 1p 1977 July 28, TLS, 1p 1979 January 8, TLS 1983 September 11, ALS, 1p [DO to RE] 1985 May 7, post card
Fallon, Peter 1977 July 20, TLS, 1p [DO to PF] 1977 August 3, ALS, 4p, w/ envelope 1977 August 20, ALS and TLS, 1p [DO to PF] 1977 September 8, ALS, 7p 1977 November 7, TLS, 1p 1977 November 8, TLS, 1p 1978 January 24, ALS, 1p 1978 April 18, ALS, 2p 1978 May 7, ALS, 2p 1978 May 17, ALS, 2p [DO to PF] 1978 June 10, TLS, 2p 1978 June 29, TLS, 2p [DO to PF] 1978 July 17, TLS 1p [DO to PF] 1978 July 20, TLS, 3p 1978 August 10, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] 1978 August 23, TLS, 2p [DO to PF] 1978 September 18, ALS, 2p 1978 October 13, ALS, 1p 1978 October 14, TLS, 2p 1978 October 18, telegram 1978 October 30, ALS, 1p 1978 November 13, ALS, 2p 1978 November 17, ALS, 1p 1979, January 1, ALS, 1p 1979 April 20, ALS, 1p 1979 July 5, ALS, 3p 1979 September 21, TLS, 1p 1979 December 10, TLS, 2p 1980 February 13, ALS, 2p 1980 July 3, ALS, 1p 1980 August 1, TLS, 2p [DO to PF] 1982 October 28, ALS, 2p 1983 January 11, TLS, 1p 1983 July 4, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] 1984 January 6, ALS, 1p 1984 February 28, ALS, 1p 1984 April 5, TLS, 1p 1984 June 14, TLS, 1p 1985 March 27, ALS, 1p 1985 April 11, post card 1985 May 14, TLS, 2p 1985 May 24, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] 1986 April 16, TLS, 1p 1987 March 27, ALS, 1p 1987 August 5, TLS, 2p 1987 August 17, TLS, 4p [DO to PF] 1987 September 17, ALS, 1p 1987 October 12, ALS, 1p 1988 March 14, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] 1988 May 21, ALS, 1p 1988 October 26, TLS, 1p 1988 December 17, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] 1988 December 25, ALS, 3p [DO to PF] 1989 August 8, TLS, 1p 1990 February 9, TLS, 1p 1990 July 24, ALS, 1p w/ invoice 1991 May 1, ALS, 1p 1992 August, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] 1992 August 10, TLS, 1p 1992 August 20, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] 1992 October 8, ALS, 1p 1992 October 9, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] 1992 October 9, ALS,1p 1992 August 10, TLS, 1p w/ invoice 1993 May 30, ALS, 1p w/envelope 2000 May 15, TLS, 1p 2000 May 17, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] undated, ALS, 1p [DO to PF] undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 2p undated, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p
Friel, Brian 1988 October 26, ALS, 1p
Grennan, Eamon 1987 August 7, ALS, 1p
Harris, Richard 1989 January 12, ALS, 1p [DO to RH] 1989 May 1, ALS, 1p [DO to RH] 1989 May 4, ALS, 1p [DO to RH]
Hartnett, Michael 1974 October 27, ALS, 1p [DO to MH] 1989 April 17, post card
Heaney, Seamus 1992 October 15, ALS, 1p [DO to SH] 1995 October 5, ALS, 1p [DO to SH] 2000 March 1, ALS, 1p [DO to SH] 2000 March 12, ALS, 1p [DO to SH] 2000 April 3, ALS, 1p [DO to SH] 2000 May 17, ALS, 1p [DO to SH] undated, ALS, 1p [DO to SH]
Hughes, Ted 1970 December, TLS, 2p 1985 January 22, post card 1988 December 25, ALS, 1p [DO to TH] 1989 February 27, post card 1997 September 5, ALS, 1p [DO to TH]
Johnston, Dillon 1986 December 30, ALS and TLS, 1p [DO to DJ] 1997 March 10, TLS, 1p 1994 October 13, TLS, 1p w/envelope undated, ALS, 1p [DO to DJ]
Kennelly, Brenden 1996 June 4, ALS, 1p [DO to BK] 1999 April 16, ALS, 1p [DO to BK] 1999 May 1, ALS, 1p w/envelope
Kiely, Benedict 1992 September 16, ALS, 1p 1996 December 18, ALS, 1p [DO to BK] 1999 August 28, ALS, 1p w/ envelope
Kinsella, Thomas 1977 January 26, ALS, 1p [DO to TK]
Kilroy, Thomas 2000 January 6, ALS, 1p [DO to TK] 2000 January 11, TLS, 1p 2000 January 14, TLS, 1p 2000 February 28, ALS, 1p [DO to TK]
Longley, Edna 1988 March 26, ALS, 1p
Longley, Michael 2000 April 4, ALS, 1p w/envelope 2000 April 17, ALS, 1p [DO to ML]
Loughlin, Bernard 1984 December 4, ALS, 3p, w/ envelope 1985 May 2, ALS, 2p 1985 May 10, ALS, 4p, w/ envelope 1987 March 13, post card 1991 November 13, TLS, 1p
Mahon, Derek 1974 December 11, ALS, 1p [DO to DM] 1975 January 1, TLS, 1p 1975 July 17, ALS, post card 1976 June 12, ALS, 2p 1977 January 14, A:S, 1p w/ envelope and poetry 1977 March 7, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1977 April 18, ALS, w/ envelope 1977 August 16, TLS, 1p w/ envelope and poetry 1977 September 17, ALS, 1p w/ envelope 1978 February 9, TLS, 1p 1978 June 1, telegram 1980 March 24, TLS, 1p 1980 March 31, post card 1980 April 4, ALS, 1p [DO to DM] 1980 May 27, TLS, 1p 1980 July 25, TLS, 1p 1981 June 9, post card 1982 August 28, TLS, 1p, w/ post card 1982 October 12, TLS, 1p 1983 May 9, TLS, 1p 1983 December 30, TLS, 1p 1984 May 28, TLS, 1p w/envelope 1984 December 27, post card 1985 January 15, post card 1985 February 4, post card 1985 March 12, TLS, 1p 1985 May 7, post card 1985 May 26, TLS, 1p 1987 July 8, TLS, 1p 1990 April 15, post card 1992 July 16, ALS, 1p [DO to DM] 1992 October 14, ALS, 1p [DO to DM] 1992 October 15, ALS, 1p [DO to DM] 1994 May 26, post card 1997 August 3, post card 1998 January 1, post card 1999 August 3, post card undated, TLS, 1p undated, ALS, 3p undated, ALS, 1p undated, TLS, 1p undated, TLS, 1p undated, TLS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p undated, TLS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p undated, TLS, 1p undated, post card undated, TLS, 1p undated, TLS, 1p 1993 December 10, Greeting card undated, Greeting card undated. Greeting card
MacDiarmond, Hugh 1974 September 12, ALS, 1p, 2 copies 1978 June 30, ALS, 1p [DO to HM]
MacIntyre, Tom 1995 July 11, ALS, 1p 1995 July 14, post card 1995 August 9, post card 1996 April 27, ALS, 1p [DO to TM] 1996 May 9, post card 1997 November 23, post card 1998 June 15, post card 1998 August 3, post card 1999 July 20, ALS, 1p [DO to TM]
Montague, John 2000 March 27, ALS, 1p [DO to JM]
Muldoon, Paul 1994 June 2, TLS, 1p 1994 September 22, TLS, 1p
Ní Chuilleanáin, Eiléan 1986 April 16, ALS, 1p 1988 May 26, ALS, 1p undated, ALS, 1p
O’Brianin, Colm 1975 June 26, TLS, 1p 1981 June 3, TLS, 1p 1981 July 14, TLS, 1p 1982 January 13, TLS, 1p 1982 November 8, TLS, 1p 1982 December 23, TLS, 1p 1983 March 8, TLS, 1p 1983 May 5, TLS, 1p 1983 July 6, TLS, 1p
O’Driscoll, Dennis 1999 October 31, ALS, 1p
O’Keeffe, Timothy 1977 September 12, TLS, 1p 1978, May 17, TLS, 1p 1978 June 30, TLS, 1p [DO to TO] 1978 December 12, TLS, 1p 1984 October 25, TLS, 1p 1987 July 20, TLS, 1p
Ormsby, Frank 1987 September 1, ALS, 1p
Princess Haya Al Hussein 1997 February 25, ALS, 1p [DO to PH] 1997 February 26, ALS, 2p 1997 March 7, ALS, 1p [DO to PH]
Queen Alia of Jordan 1976 January 28, ALS, 1p [DO to QA]
Raine, Craig 1982 November 15, post card
Raine, Kathleen 1994 July 23, TLS, 1p
Reid, Christopher 1992 June 2, ALS, 1p (2 drafts) [DO to CR] 1992 July 16, TLS, 1p 1995 May 5, TLS, 1p
Said, Edward 1987 January 29, ALS, 1p [DO to ES]
Simmons, James 1984 December 4, TLS, 1p w/ photograph
Simms, Jacqueline 1978 June 29, TLS, 1p 1978 July 17, TLS, 1p [DO to JS] 1995 September 1, ALS, 1p (2 drafts) [DO to JS] 1995 September 8, ALS and TLS, 1p [DO to JS] 1995 September 16, TLS, 1p
Smith, Michael 1974 November 5, ALS, 1p [DO to MS] 1977 May 9, post card
Vendler, Helen 1986 November 3, TLS, 1p